i have got some major major explaining
to do about the mycelium resistance
headquarters
so i have bamboozled not only the hip
but i have bamboozled some of you guys
which probably made it all the more
convincing so let's explain it all
started
last episode when i met impulse to talk
about
some mycelium shenanigans and we went
and had a look at what the hep were
doing i'm sorry the hip
and there was a clip that we recorded
that i had to cut out of my video oh
look it was mumbo
what's he doing
oh self-portrait mumbo
he's looking for me
it's a work in progress
needs more
facial hair
i'm sure someone will add some
so true so
for context let's watch that clip that
me and impulse had to cut from our
videos for this to make sense
over here check it out wait
okay watch this button come up here
quickly oh dude fall oh dude
check it out man i already saw this you
got a cub with this right like this
button here oh don't press the button
don't press the button it's triggered no
i added something new look look if you
come over here this opens up
extra secret
new secret hallway
okay
you're gonna love this next time secret
tunnels are my favorite thing dude every
time you get someone just make a new
tunnel
yes what have you linked this up to
have you bring this up to our base
no our base is nowhere near here what
are you talking about oh dude this isn't
our base
you didn't you didn't you recreated the
entire mycelium headquarters i did it's
a replica dude what this thing took me
like six hours to make
yeah me too
me too
goodness oh my goodness
that's what i was thinking like a bogus
plan to throw them off
oh my goodness it's happening
yes
that is perfect
for mary's
the plan is to overthrow scar and make
mumbo for mumbo mare again dude this is
so mumbo doesn't have a clue what's
going on he said to me the other day
like oh there's something going on with
my ceiling and i'm just like nah nothing
much like okay cool the signs aren't
enough i think we better
make it worth their while visiting if
you know what i mean ah a little extra
flare yeah a little extra yeah a little
extra flare let's put it okay
okay i got some up my sleeve i know
exactly where your head's at
i just showed you the the fake base yes
the real base i showed you the fake
headquarters
in order to get somebody to actually
find it and go in and fall for all the
false information i think you should
show it on video of you entering it and
make it seem like you're entering the
the real one
i mean just pretend you're entering the
real one and you accidentally did a show
okay i'll i'll cut it so it looks like
i've just gone to the i'll go to the
area i'll press the button i'll leave
enough time to hear some pistons but
then cut and then i'll be inside the
base and i may even cut it so i'm inside
this base
and that should be enough
to leave them there
so impulse basically has created an
entire decoy hq
and he created a button here which he
asked me
to record
showing
meaning that it was always going to lure
someone from help or hip to come down
here and find it i can't believe still
can't believe that he made an exact
replica now those of you that had keen
eyes realized that this wasn't identical
there was some bits missing and wasn't
exactly the same
so what happened was false saw me enter
the fake base which i quite poorly cut
into my video
and then this is what happened false
then followed that footage just like we
planned and fell into the fake mycelium
headquarters
unfortunately she didn't actually get
killed by the prank the impulse had set
so
in the end it ended up being a bit of a
failure but at the same time we did
massively bamboozle her so it just goes
to show
the mind games are extremely real
and no one knows where the base is
we have been bamboozling everyone from
day one i see so many comments about
people saying i know where the base is i
know where the base is the bedrock the
sea i see where you're flying in i
promise you no one knows where it is
it's honestly so hidden and we're taking
it very seriously so now that that big
reveal is out of the way
and you can see the level of mind games
that we are now currently entering
let's crack on with the rest of the
video because we've got quite a lot to
do and i once again need to enter the
mycelium headquarters so my tasks for
today are two things number one is sort
out our storage problem i've set up a
bunch of this so that i can start making
a proper storage room for all of our
mycelium which we all have a massive
plan for
my second task for today for the
mycelium resistance
is to release
the sheep i've been breeding up a bunch
of them i even got some more wheat in
order to do that and my goodness i mean
this is
i i think the mycelium resistance might
end up breaking hermitcraft
through the power of sheep
never thought i'd say that they are a
powerful animal and they're all wearing
extremely cool sunglasses i may need to
make this pen a little bit bigger this
is gonna cause some serious lag however
we have not got ourselves enough sheep
to make this project work
so we need a lot more
and that's going to take a few minutes
or hours depending on how successful
this is but we need a lot more sheep be
free
there we go it's a bit more space for
them so they're not colliding and
causing so much lag so the plan is to
release all of these sheep later on
before we get into all the mycelium
resistance headquarters stuff there's
something we need to do again it
happened a few episodes ago but i spent
days and i mean days collecting leaves
to try and sneak a win
at the hedge games which is just over
here
and i heard
that the winners have been announced and
it's rendog
and me
i also won i was on his team so i think
we should get ourselves in a call with
ren and we get to choose our prize the
winner gets to pick
the first pile so it's between this one
and this one so let's give ren a call
green i can't actually believe it but we
won i can believe it because we spent
like three days collecting leaves
yeah that's actually true
[Laughter]
but we won the whole week
dude this is amazing i never win
anything yes the winner is red dog yes
seeing as this was like your group i'll
let you do the the honors of choosing
and then uh we'll what do you want to do
split it down the middle
yeah we gotta go 50 50. you know
yeah okay which one do you want
i it's we it's gotta be the near the
right yeah you know okay it's too tasty
it's too beautiful i'm glad you said
that i'm so glad you said that i also
want the bark in print so this is the
one i think yeah this is the one we get
beacons and everything dude it's amazing
let's take it down and see what we got
right what do we got we're having having
to use this hop up because we haven't
got anything else yeah right actual
minecrafters dude this makes it super
easy so we get 10 diamonds each five
near the right blocks each 20 gold and
two beacons
oh there we go and you can have the bark
in prince since it was uh it was your
group well all of that grinding down
forests definitely worth it green thanks
bernie bro thanks bernie thanks bernie
yeah well yeah this is you know 10
diamond blocks is a lot but like
comparing what i get from the barge it's
actually not that much but the netherite
blocks that's the big one
that is the big one
yep whoops combining them again
green we got one more bit of business to
attend to my friend we certainly do
yes here in the the laboratory of uh r d
random dog yes i'd just like to say i
have created a wonderfully scientific
machine to breed mushrooms
you've gone back to 2011.
i was just thinking to myself oh yours
looks so much more professional than
mine mine's just a pen full of sheep
well listen it's going to do the trick
we still need to get the sheep into the
mupplicator yo
um so
i i don't really know how to do this i
guess like i can jury rig the machine a
little bit here with some fence edge yep
this should potentially work maybe could
you get the sheep into there somehow
well i think there's probably enough of
them that we can just like they'll just
head on in
there we go okay perfect
science
science are we ready should we unleash
go
okay
let there go there push it they're all
going this is exactly what i oh man
there we go oh my goodness
it's working it is working
it's working wait there's there's xp
balls in there we've had losses
now we just need to know whether they're
actually getting out the other side the
there's a traffic jam over in sheep
central come on
oh no i'm in
i'm careful dude goodbye
oh it's working
the first the first recruits are now out
i'm having excellent i'm having to lure
them out with uh there's there's a
serious traffic jam okay i'm trying to
shove some more of the sheep into the
muplicator but uh i'm having to break
the top because they're all drowning oh
excellent it's working there's way more
than i imagined right my plan is to
change out some of the blocks that are
grass into mycelium so that it can all
start to spread green it's actually
working genuinely is working they are
decimating the grass i have i'm yet to
see a single block of mycelium spread
but it's working they are taking down
the grass i can't i just can't believe
it like in my trial it really didn't
work that well
it took three years brilliantly and
they're spreading out they're going all
over the place
the mushrooms are back on the island the
native species of the island have
returned we are restoring the shopping
district to its former glory dude this
this is definitely not science this is
getting kind of scary this is illegal
i think the server's gonna break to be
honest i can't i literally can't get out
i'm not even moving i'm just jumping and
getting pushed how help
all right you're good sorry round two
round two yeah we've adjusted the
placator
wait do i need to open this up for them
yeah you open that up
i'll open these up here they come here
we go okay sheep you gotta move though
there we go please work hey
this is going better than before
i love yes
that's brilliant
why is it so funny
[Laughter]
there's something
go my agents go
this was a this was a mistake friend you
okay in there no
no i'm not i'll tell you what i'll meet
you at the i'll meet you at the exit
okay okay
oh i'm out oh my goodness
yes
eat my pretties eat
demolish the grass i think we might have
broken the server though dude
i'm feeling the
super laggy and just bringing a load of
these sheep i'm just bringing them all
into mumbo's new shop whatever this
thing is
he's just afk
standard mumbo
and and you do this
i did
i caught you in the act
told you it was all mumbo and
mechanically it's actually working and
the heat
the hiss it is the hip are gonna have to
actually do something about this i
thought i'd have to abandon this project
and the sheep wouldn't work but it's
there it is working
sometimes i even surprise myself it's
been a day since we released the sheep
and as you can see it's genuinely
working the mycelium is slowly spreading
and for some reason it's far more
satisfying to see it spread like this
than to just have to mine it all out and
place mycelium down so overall an
enormous success i don't think this
could have gone any better to be honest
but it turns out in just one day
someone's already shaved the cows
they're back they're just normal cows
now
what's wrong with mushrooms i have to
say though i kind of hope that the hep
team the hip team get a move on and
start doing something about these sheep
because they are actually causing a bit
of a lag problem there there are far
too many sheep in the shopping district
but that's not our problem that's town
hall's problem do you see mumbo's face
changed again
pep life join hep get cake that's pretty
good and also we saw mumbo working on a
self-portrait over there
man he really is handsome and humble so
let's take a look at what this is
welcome to the hermitcraft
spookification chamber with halloween on
the horizon it's time for some hermit
horrors set your spawn remove all your
items deposit 16 diamonds jump in and
then you're spooky woo
dude why is there 40 pages
in this book has he just filled this
with empty paper oh no this process is
not currently reverse that's the fine
print
he couldn't put small text in a
minecraft book so he just decided to put
it right at the end of 40 pages okay so
this gives you a spooky halloween
minecraft skin
i think we'll come back to this next
episode so now we need to go and do what
we wanted to do at the start of the
episode which is make a storage chamber
so
let's go and do that now
[Music]
the cuts are getting sloppier i realize
that
oh and also hilariously i decided to
come up with my own decked out box black
shulker boxes that i will put in the
shopping district and they have
different messages for mycelium spread
the spores fight town hall it's about
the principle so we'll put these in the
shopping district after we have made our
storage room so let's crack on and we're
not gonna do anything too fancy just a
space to store some shulker boxes so
this can be put to be like you know like
look at this shulker box storage monster
chest monster is on the loose we need to
get this organized so
let's get cracking
[Music]
nothing over the top nothing too
spectacular but at least we can keep
this base a little more clean and tidy
without all these shulkers everywhere so
that's a pretty good thing
and i also counted it up we have 34
shulker boxes full of mycelium this is a
serious amount of dirt so
i don't know what we're going to do with
all this but i'm sure it'll come in
useful also
above base
captain shenanigans over here has made
possibly the best feature
of the base so far
you throw the pearl in this water and it
keeps it oh no did it wrong i don't know
what i did help no
you throw the end of pearl in water
there we go
and then now that ender pearl is in
stasis so basically if every single
person throws an ender pearl you see
ethos is there what happens is if you
press the button or the piston activates
touching the ender pearl and allowing
you to fall into the meeting room so
we essentially have our own
emergency meeting
system
i don't know if it's actually linked up
to the giant red button that we made
last episode but if it is oh man head of
shenanigans indeed so let's go and take
all of these fake decked out boxes and
put them in the shopping district things
are really starting to shape up for team
mycelium i'm gonna put decked out boxes
where i always look but never find ones
in the hope that people will find it oh
man
this is the perfect spot for a decked
out box on top of the witch's hat tango
must have so much fun with this
i always look in the chest monster and
there's never any here
b-dubs has made one of those like
blow-up wiggly whirly things i don't
know what they're called they you know
what i mean the fabric people that have
like hot air blown through them and then
they just go
wibbly whirly people so put one on the
mouth of the llama and one more
i think we got to put it
i'll put hep in the crea
just there that'll do
perfect they have absolutely zero
defense there's a bunch of billboards
that have turned up
we know
we know how to deal with dirt hep
are they calling us dirt is that what's
happening here i thought they dealt with
grass i feel like you don't know how to
deal with dirt at all
man where have all the sheep gone
well the mycelium has spread
very very significantly
look at this this worked so well but
where have the sheep gone there was like
a million more sheep than there are
right now well either way somehow this
entire episode ended up being mycelium
resistance related which is not what i
planned but here we are i just spent all
day in the shopping district so let's go
back to the base hold on what did i just
see i think i've just figured out
they're like
they're like the monsters inc guys 23
19.
oh no
i think i've just figured out what
happened to the sheep
i think the dogs got them if you needed
any more proof that these these are the
ba i thought
i thought that said hip look
hip
hep hip
hip hep
yep
oh man they've
uh they've taken some of our sheep don't
worry boys we'll get you out of there so
let's go back to our base because
mycelium is taking over the world at the
moment so i've been working on my base
and it is getting pretty massive check
it out i've recently built this giant
rocket and a bunch of industrial stuff
which i plan on making some farms in to
get this place
getting really productive so check it
out this is my enormous tower i am
really proud of what i've built here
it's not spawn proof as you can see
bit of a zombie there
but check it out it's a really good
build to be able to fly into
and massive i mean look at the size of
this thing goes all the way down to
bedrock you have any idea how long this
took
to mine out so let's go and get some
more work done okay that was the hermit
challenge take credit for someone else's
base that was full symmetry's base guys
not mine that is another hermit
challenge complete i found a bunch of
hidden chickens that were like still in
here so it turns out i haven't done all
of the ones i needed to do scare another
hermit
well we'll have to do that when we get
an opportunity you must have been so
confused i mean it felt really weird
because i was like flying around
foster's base going yeah look at what
i've made and i've never actually been
to false's base before so i was like
where's my portal
where where's all this stuff that i've
supposedly built perfect now on to our
real base the one that we really did why
eggs everywhere the one that we really
did make ourselves the glorious green
mansion and i've been thinking to myself
i want to make this thing even more
productive so i had an idea
behind here behind all this black
concrete
there is quite a substantial bit of
space now i've lit it up because it was
a
mob spawners dream and that got me
thinking
well why don't we just make this a mob
spawner
so i think i answered my own question by
lighting it up what this place is going
to be really good for i obviously over
calculated when i started mining this
out and i don't think it would be a
massive
issue or task to mine all of this out
and turn it into a bunch of platforms
for a giant mob sport maybe not a giant
mob spawner but a mob spawner because it
is good to have a stock of things that i
don't have all the time like string or
bones
and maybe i can expand that into a few
more farms so my mansion can become its
own industrial area and the reason for
that is because there's actually not
many caves around here at all and the
ones that there are i've lit up already
so this makes it prime
prime real estate for making a mob
spawner so that will be my plan my task
for next episode much like the sugarcane
farm that i put off for a long time i
want to dabble in some work on the base
and the mycelium resistance because i
don't want to abandon this place i want
to keep working and i want to keep
making some cool stuff over here so i'm
thinking
this needs to be finished because
realistically this isn't finished and
then i need to kind of replicate the
success over here to the right hand side
and then maybe one day we'll look at the
back of the mansion
maybe not at this point i feel like i
can't i feel like i genuinely can't look
at the back of the mansion for the rest
of the season i feel like everything has
to be at the front but anyway i think
that is all we have time for today we
did get quite a lot done
and i'm extremely excited about what's
going on with the mycelium resistance
hence i spent an entire episode on it
there's some very exciting plans and
things to come so i can't wait to share
them all with you and i can't wait to
use the emergency meeting button it's
gonna be excellent but of course it only
works if they're online so i have to
wait for the team to be online the
resistance to be online to be able to
call an emergency meeting
okay so that's all for now and i shall
see you in the next video good bye
you